Charles Wilson

charleswilson1991@googlemail.com

Objective

Experienced and accomplished full-stack software developer with 5 years experience building and maintaining large scale, high TPS, complex services, and websites. Looking to use this experience to build new innovative and exciting systems in a full-stack or backend engineering role.

Work Experience

Software Development Engineer

Amazon Development Centre London

February 2016 — Present

Video Commerce Experience Clients Team

Responsibilities included:

Full-stack development of the UI and client experience for the Prime sign up funnels on web (440mm views, 2018), mobile web (265mm views, 2018) and big-screen devices (32mm views, 2018); on-call work and out-of-hours live site issue support including low SLA pager response responsibilities; any other day-to-day duties.

Notable achievements:

- Designed, implemented and released an updated FireTV sign up experience including payment entry. Testing saw a 90% increase in target customer conversion rates, forecasting to \$58mm additional revenue for the year across all Prime Video Subscription Video on Demand (SVOD).
- Project lead for the expansion of Prime Video Channels subscriptions into the European region, including the UK and German markets (60 channels UK, 56 channels DE to date.) Included managing multiple stakeholders such as tech teams in other sections of the Video organisation, as well as non-tech teams such as Merchandising, Marketing and Localisation teams.
- Completed a total rewrite of the web, mobile web, and big-screen webview experienced from a fully Perl Mason monolithic stack to a ReactJS widgetized solution.

Software Development Engineer

Amazon Development Centre London

September 2014 — Feb 2016

LOVEFILM Disks ByPost Clients Team

Responsibilities included:

Full-stack development of the UI, subscription management, and client experience for the LOVEFiLM DVD and BlueRay disk rental including web, mobile web, and android and iPhone applications, averaging 400k total active users. Responsibilities included maintaining and expanding the customer interaction points; such as rental list management, details page, account management page, and internal customer services tooling.

Notable achievements:

- Implemented a custom customer authentication integration for the ByPost iPhone and Android mobile app based in Apache Cordova, with an average of 10k daily active users.
- Implemented a new subscription creation and LOVEFiLM to Amazon Video subscription migration system. (Java, SpringMVC)
- Expanded the website using a new Java framework to include a new automated FAQ and help section to automatically fix common customer issues such as torn return envelopes with automated re-dispatch, greatly reducing Customer Service load.

Software Development Engineer, Intern

Amazon Development Centre London

June 2013 — August 2013

Digital Video Website Playback Team

- Implemented an internal web tool in Java Spark framework to allow for tracking of issues and learning resources.
- Implemented the first desktop iteration of the Amazon Video XRay feature on the Silverlight website player, while ensuring minimal impact on CPU usage (<1% increase) and playback experience, with no drop is QOS metrics. (C#, XHTML)

Education

Software Engineering

Durham University

October 2011 — July 2014

- Classification: 2:1.
- Thesis: "Efficiently visualising the state of cellular automata using Conway's Game of Life." Efficiently run and render a Conway's Game of Life with an infinitely sized board with on the fly rule set adjustments using large scale parallelization.

Languages, Technologies & Skills

- Languages: Java, Python (scripting), C#, C++ (minor experience)
- Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS & SASS, Javascript (ES6, TypeScript), Node.js, ReactJS
- Services Technologies: Java SpringMVC, RESTful Java service creation